Guide to Barge Canal Contracts
Erie Canal Museum
Barge Canal Contracts
1905 - 1949
35 bound volumes and two sets of loose papers containing blueprints and plans for Barge Canal Contracts
35 bound volumes
New York (State). State Engineer and Surveyor
Erie Canal Museum 318 Erie Boulevard East Syracuse, NY 13202
The Collection is open for research use.
The New York State Barge Canal is a nationally significant work of early twentieth century engineering and construction that affected transportation and maritime commerce. The Barge Canal system's four main branches, the Erie, Champlain, Oswego, and Cayuga-Seneca canals, are much enlarged versions of waterways that were initially constructed during the 1820s.
Erie Canal (N.Y.)
35 bound volumes and two sets of loose papers containing blueprints and plans for Barge Canal contracts.
- Barge Canal Contracts--Cayuga Seneca Canal
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts F, G, H, I, J, K, Cayuga Seneca Canal, 1918; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates of Barge Canal Contracts F-K of the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.01
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts A, A-1, Cayuga Seneca Canal, 1914; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates of Barge Canal Contracts A, A-1 for the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.03
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal-Oswego Terminal Contracts No.1, M-30, 30, 31, 33, 33-P, 48, 80, 82, 89, 89-A, 106, 122, 137, 213, 226, 237. Cayuga-Seneca Canal, Bound volume of blueprints relating to Oswego Terminal Contracts No.1, M-30, 30, 31, 33, 33-P, 48, 80, 82, 89, 89-A, 106, 122, 137, 213, 226, 237 for Cayuga-Seneca Canal, and Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.14
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts W, P, Cayuga Seneca Canal, 1921; Loose blueprints relating to final estimates of contracts W, P for the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.15
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contract B, Cayuga Seneca Canal, 1910 - 1913; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contract B for the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.22
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contract C, Cayuga Seneca Canal, 1913 - 1916; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contract C for the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.23
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts L, M, P, Q, R, T, U, Cayuga-Seneca Canal, 1915 - 1917; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts L, M, P, Q, R, T, U, for the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.29
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts D, E, Cayuga Seneca Canal, 1914 - 1917; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts D, E, for the Cayuga and Seneca Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.33
- Barge Canal Contracts--Erie Canal
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 12, Vol. 1, Erie Canal, 1915; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates of Barge Canal Contract 12 for the Erie Canal.; Includes item FC 2019.05.02
  - Final Estimate; Barge Canal Improvements U.S. 26, 27, 42, Oneida Lake, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates on barge canal contracts 26, 27, 42 for Oneida Lake on the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.07
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 132, 139, 141, 148, 153, 154, 158, 159, 164, 165, 167, 172, 173, 182, 184, 188, 193, 198, 198, 208, 233, Erie Canal, 1916 - 1918; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 132, 139, 141, 148, 153, 154, 158, 159, 164, 165, 167, 172, 173, 182, 184, 188, 193, 198, 198, 208, 233 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.10
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 9217, 9328, 9602, 9487, 9781, 53, 9593, 9778, 201, 322, 34, M-62, 418, Erie Canal, 1949; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 9217, 9328, 9602, 9487, 9781, 53, 9593, 9778, 201, 322, 34, M-62, 418 for the Erie Canal.; Includes item FC 2019.05.19
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 46 A, 46 B, Erie Canal, 1917; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 46 A and B for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.20
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 12 Vol. 2, Erie Canal, 1907 - 1915; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contract 12 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.26
  - Final Estimates; Terminal Contract 20, 28, 28 A, 46, 59, 60, Erie Canal, 1915 - 1917; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for terminal contracts 20, 28, 28 A, 46, 59, 60 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.28
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 5, 5-A, 7, Erie Canal, 1905 - 1907; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 5, 5-A, 7 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.30
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 46, Erie Canal, 1908 - 1913; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates of barge canal contract 46 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.31
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts U.S. 5, Erie Canal, 1935 - 1937; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contract 5 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.34
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 44 A, 45, Erie Canal, 1911; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 44A, 45 for the Erie Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.35
- Barge Canal Contracts--Oswego Canal
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 37 Vol. 1, Oswego Canal, 1910 - 1912; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates on barge canal contract 37 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.06
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Improvements U.S. 19, Oswego Canal, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contract 19 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.08
  - Final Estimates; U.S. 28, 57, Oswego Canal, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 28, 57 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.12
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 35, Oswego Canal, 1907 - 1912; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates on barge canal contract 35 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.16
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 37 Vol. 2, Oswego Canal, 1915; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates of barge canal contract 37 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.17
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 10 A, 10 B, 10 C, Oswego Canal, 1914; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 10 A, B, C for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.18
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 10, Oswego Canal, 1906 - 1916; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contract 10 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.24
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 37-R, 39, 205, Oswego Canal, 1913; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 37-R, 39, 205 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.25
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts, Highways, Oswego Canal, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts concerning highways near the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.32
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 53-57, Oswego Canal, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 53-57 for the Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.36
  - Maps relating to Oswego River and Canal, Loose maps relating to Oswego River and Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.37
- Barge Canal Contracts--Erie and Oswego Canals
  - Barge Canal Improvement for Raising Bridges. Contracts 22, 29, 51, 53, 58, 67, 1939; Bound volume of blueprints relating to contracts 22, 29, 51, 53, 58, 67 for raising bridges. Erie and Oswego Canals; Includes item FC 2019.05.04
  - Final Estimates; U.S. 14. Erie, Oswego Barge Canal, 1938; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates on contract 14 for the Erie and Oswego Barge Canals; Includes item FC 2019.05.05
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 100, 101, 102, 103, 104, 108, 117, 116, 121, Erie-Oswego Canal, 1913 - 1915; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 100-104, 108, 117, 116, 121 for the Erie and Oswego Canal; Includes item FC 2019.05.09
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts No. 5181-U.S. 32, No. 4143-U.S. 7, Erie-Oswego Canal, 1935 - 1937; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts No. 5181-U.S. 32, No. 4143-U.S. 7 for the Erie and Oswego Canals; Includes item FC 2019.05.11
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 90, 90A, 93, 99, Erie-Oswego Canal, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 90, 90A, 93, 99 for the Erie and Oswego Canals; Includes item FC 2019.05.13
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 33, 13, 22, 22-A, Erie and Oswego Canal, 1912; Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 33, 13, 22, 22-A for the Erie and Oswego Canals; Includes item FC 2019.05.21
  - Final Estimates; Barge Canal Contracts 78, 79, 80, 84, 85, Erie-Oswego Canals, Bound volume of blueprints relating to final estimates for barge canal contracts 78, 79, 80, 84, 85 for the Erie and Oswego Canals; Includes item FC 2019.05.27